Guide to the Stephen Zelencik Collection of Advanced Micro Devices Video M2255
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stephen Zelencik collection of Advanced Micro Devices video
c. 1963-1998
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Zelencik, Stephen
M2255
1.5 Linear Feet: 2 boxes
Content Description
Advanced Micro Devices, Inc. (AMD) is an American multinational semiconductor company based in Sunnyvale, California, that develops computer processors and related technologies. After having begun in sales at Amphenol in the early 1960s, Stephen J. Zelencik started working for Fairchild Semiconductor in 1964-5, migrating to Advanced Micro Devices in 1970 at the request of founder Jerry Sanders, who had left Fairchild to start AMD the year before. He was AMD's first outside salesperson, eventually serving as Senior Vice President and Chief Marketing Executive. Zelencik retired from AMD in 2003. This small collection contains 12 VHS videotapes and 1 DVD-R related to AMD, as well as a set of slides from Amphenol.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephen Zelencik, circa 2015.
Related Materials
Stanford Special Collections holds other material on AMD, including two videos which may streamed from our library catalog. Both are from the papers of artist Ruth Asawa (who was contracted for a project that was later cancelled): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/gc069ns8218 https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/xn194cr3447
Also, the transcript of a 2013 Zelencik interview for the Silicon Genesis series is available here: https://silicongenesis.stanford.edu/transcripts/zelencik.htm
Computer industry -- United States -- History; Semiconductor industry -- History -- California; Zelencik, Stephen; Advanced Micro Devices (Firm)
- AMD RISCY Business (VHS) (Box 1)
- Ray Bradbury at AMD Sales Conference (VHS), 1994 (Box 1)
  Bradbury, Ray, 1920-2012
- Purdue Distinguished Engineering Award (VHS), April 24, 1998 (Box 1)
- AMD Report #50 (VHS) (Box 1)
- AMD- Hamilton/Hallmark Sears Point Raceway (VHS) (Box 1)
- AMD Report #33 (VHS), 1985 (Box 1)
- AMD "In Your Shoes" (VHS), July 24, 1995 (Box 1)
- Sales Conference Opener, Dinner, Slide Show & Candid Shots (VHS), 1981 (Box 1)
- AMD: Advanced Micro Devices, Sales Conference '94- Steve Zelencik (VHS), 1994 (Box 1)
- Newport Beach * for Steve Z. Frank Baffi * South Orange Co. * Bert Barden * Paul Neher * John Kramer * John Roeser * Dan Montenegro * Paul Stutrenberg (VHS), September 1984 (Box 1)
- Big Dogs: Frank Baffi (DVD-R), September 1st, 1988 (Box 1)
- Woodside Tape- Watch End + Books (VHS) (Box 2)
- 1995 International Sales Conference Highlights (VHS) (Box 2)
- Early Packing Technology - Amphenol (slides), 1963-64 (Box 2)